# **Carson Reinke**

## IT Development Manager / IT Full Stack Developer

A knowledgeable and thorough Full Stack Developer with attention to detail. Driven and self-motivated, and therefore effective at completing tasks with minimal supervision. Confident leader and enthusiastic communicator. Over 15 years experience participating in the hands-on creation and maintenance of hundreds of websites within the IT field.

Demands level of excellence from employees and co-workers which mirrors one's own execution of work completion. Dissects complex requirements with tenacity, covering every possible solution.

Able to technically lead, provide direction, mentor, facilitate, troubleshoot, and above all set-up as well as execute a wide variety of projects for immediate success.

## **Expertise**

Web Development Ecommerce Email

Regression Testing Automation Integrations

R&D Reporting Technical Products

# **Experience**

#### June 2017 - June 2020

Brand Labs | Ecommerce agency | Rochester, MI | https://brandlabs.us

Title: Development Manager

Summary: Responsibilities include providing day to day technical management, procedural guidance and keeping the 8 person development team on track. Role also includes writing documentation, coding standards, consulting, and deployment procedures. Reviewing Developer completed projects for quality standards along with supporting the sales team with project estimates and relaying technical interpretation of client requirements. Architecting new projects and technical products based on experience of Ecommerce systems. Hands-on development of components and projects. Tech: Node.js PHP Laravel MySQL

## July 2011 - June 2017

Brand Labs | Ecommerce agency | Rochester, MI | https://brandlabs.us

<u>Title</u>: Technical Products Manager

<u>Summary</u>: Responsibilities include managing, supporting, and implementing new features on an email remarketing SaaS product named Autoresponder Max (<a href="https://autorespondermax.com">https://autorespondermax.com</a>). Improving quality by introducing larger test coverage. Supported and managed hosting servers. Provided management with new technical product ideas to further sales and support. <a href="https://example.com/Tech:">Tech:</a> Ruby Rails MySQL

#### October 2007 - October 2011

Brand Labs | Ecommerce agency | Rochester, MI | https://brandlabs.us

# **Personal**

<u>carson@reinke.co</u>

248-379-6697 | 248-693-1204

1160 Dolliver Drive Rochester Hills, MI

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cars onreinke

https://github.com/carsonreinke https://twitter.com/carsonreinke https://reinke.co

https://stackoverflow.com/story/carsonreinke

# **Technical Skills**

## Languages

Ruby	••••
JS	
PHP	••••
Java/J2EE	
Objective-C	
C/C++	
T-SQL	••••
ASP (Classic)	••••
VBA	••••
C#	
Python	
HTML	
CSS	
Go	

#### Libraries

Ruby on Rails, Laravel, Rake, Grunt, Jest, Mocha, Resque, Title: Development Manager

<u>Summary</u>: Established team and procedures to start implementing store themes on Ecommerce platform Volusion. Created a streamlined process to take design compositions into implementation for a high volume number of projects. Built and managed a new development team.

Tech: PHP MySQL ASP

## September 2004 - October 2007

Marketing Associates | Marketing incentives agency | Bloomfield Hills, MI | <a href="https://www.marketingassociates.com">https://www.marketingassociates.com</a>

<u>Title</u>: Developer / System Architect

<u>Summary</u>: Responsibilities included implementation and maintenance of various projects including any source code and databases. Assisted with development and maintenance of common functionality for all projects. Common functionality included special logging tools, PDF manipulation tools, and service layers for custom business rules. Improved application configuration company wide so new builds do not need to be created for different environments.

Tech: Java J2EE Oracle DB

## August 2002 - September 2004

Sv3 Media Group | Web development agency | Rochester, MI | <a href="http://bit.ly/2uqRLF6">http://bit.ly/2uqRLF6</a>

Title: Developer

<u>Summary</u>: Responsibilities included source code, databases, and server maintenance, also component library development and maintenance. Almost all projects worked on included customer contact and title on projects was Technical Lead and/or Lead Developer.

Tech: ASP VBA SQL Server

# **Personal Projects**

## **Student Selected Seating Generator**

https://student-selected-seating-generator.reinke.co/ https://github.com/carsonreinke/student-selected-seating-generator

Tool to help teachers arrange students in a classroom based on their own preferences for each other.

Tech: Node.js Vue.js Vuex

#### **Email Marketing Report**

http://emailmarketing.report/

https://github.com/carsonreinke/emailmarketing.report

Automatically collected email marketing reports.

Tech: Ruby Rails

#### **Nginx Redirection Module**

https://github.com/carsonreinke/redirector/

https://github.com/carsonreinke/redirector.github.io/

https://redirector.website

Nginx static module for redirection from DNS. Redirects a domain based on proper DNS entry of the domain.

Tech: C

MiniTest (Ruby), VCR (Ruby), Selenium WebDriver, Bower, Android SDK, Vue.js, WebPack

#### **Software**

Volusion, BigCommerce, Magento, Shopify, Mozu/Kibo MailChimp, Constant Contact, PowerReviews, Wordpress Email On Acid, Litmus, Browserstack, MediaBin

#### Tools

Nginx, Phusion Passenger, Apache, NodeJS, NPM Git, SVN, Unbound, Solr, Nagios, GitHub, GitLab MySQL, Oracle Database, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Redis, XCode, Scrapy

#### **Others**

JSON, XML, XSD SMTP, IMAP, POP3, DKIM, SPF, DMARC, OAuth, REST, Server-Sent Events (SSE) Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Google Optimize, Optimizely Google Site Search, Google Search Console Web Content Accessibility

#### **Education / Certifications**

- Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science from Lawrence Technological University, Southfield, MI, Class of 2002
- Lambda lota Tau (Honors Society)
- First Place Winner of Robofest 2000, Judge's Award for Advance Exhibition at Robofest 2002
- Association of Computing Machinery (ACM), Student Chair
- Google Tag Manager Partner Certified

#### **Hobbies**

- Mountain biking
- Bike maintenance
- Fishing

## **Node Very Important Packages**

https://carsonreinke.github.io/node-vip/ https://github.com/carsonreinke/node-vip

Analyzing Node packages to identify which are the most important to the community.

Tech: Node.js

#### **HTML Conditional Comment**

https://github.com/carsonreinke/html-conditional-comment Evaluate, parse, and tokenize HTML conditional comments

Tech: Ruby

## WkHtml

https://github.com/carsonreinke/wkhtml Ruby native gem for bindings against wkhtmltopdf

Tech: Ruby C

#### **SCP for Git**

https://github.com/carsonreinke/git-scp Utility to do secure copy from git command

Tech: Bash